# KRITHIKA N

# SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Bangalore +91 9739110297 krithi.n12@gmail.com

# PROFILE SUMMARY

Worked at IBM/Kyndryl for 7 years in various domains. Started out as a technical support associate then progressed as an IM and now currently working as a Linux system administrator. Adept at working cross-departmentally with co-management and top-level leadership. Excellent trainer and mentor.

### SKILLS

Staff education and training Technical issue analysis

Good communication, organizational and leadership skills Knowledge of cloud services and RHEL

# EDUCATION

**PG-Dipolma** 2014 - 2015

PADMASHREE INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT AND SCIENCES Nutraceuticals and Food Processing

**B.E.** 2009 – 2013

M.S. RAMAIAH INSTITUTE OF TECNOLOGY Biotechnology

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **System Administrator**

July, 2021 - 2022

Kyndryl, Bangalore

- · Resolved vulnerabilities by making improvements to network security.
- · Resolved trouble tickets to reduce the backlog.
- Resolved issues and escalated problems with knowledgeable support and quality service.
- Installed and updated AV on Linux servers as per client requirements.
- Coordinated with the compliance team to make sure all the new RHEL servers built were compliant.
- Prepare and present RCA on weekly basis for the team.

# **Work Load Manager**

March, 2020 - June, 2021

IBM, Bangalore

- Supervised work of contracted employees to keep on task for timely completion.
- · Created plans and communicated deadlines to ensure projects were completed on time.
- · Onboarding and offboarding of employees
- Used coordination and planning skills to achieve results according to schedule.
- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and a fast-paced atmosphere.
- Led projects and analyzed data to identify opportunities for improvement.
- · Participated in team-building activities to enhance working relationships.

# **Incident Manager**

November, 2018 - March, 2020

IBM, Bangalore

- Ensure that activities within a process are being performed at a high level of quality and that it meets its associated Service Level Agreements.
- Directly works with Tier 1 Support to ensure proper recording of incidents Determines if an incident needs to be escalated according to priority and severity of the issue.
- Ensure that Incidents assigned to their Support Groups are resolved and that service is restored
  Monitor the Incidents and manage workload in their respective queues to ensure that Service Level
  Agreement and Operational Level Agreement are respected Identify Incidents for review Participate
  in Incident review following major Incidents Identify potential problems and/or increasing trend of
  repetitive Incidents Create Knowledge with repeatable procedures with a goal of reducing the
  number of Incidents Escalate all process issues to the Incident Manager.
- Assessed incident priority based upon the impact on business and escalate issues as necessary.
- Handled high-priority incidents with exceptional poise and composure, making quick decisions in an effort to reduce overall impact.

#### **Team Lead**

July, 2017 - October, 2018

# IBM, Bangalore

- Created and submitted knowledge articles.
- Process trainer for the pooled accounts.
- Worked with change management in the creation of changes and was also involved in following up
  with different teams to ensure the successful implementation of the change.
- Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.
- · Created spreadsheets using Microsoft Excel for daily, weekly, and monthly reporting
- Mentored and guided employees to foster proper completion of assigned duties.
- Built strong relationships with customers through positive attitude and attentive response.
- Positioned as the go-to person for up to 30 staff members, troubleshooting complex administrative and training issues promptly.
- Coordinated weekly meetings for internal and external groups.
- Cross-trained and provided backup for customer service managers.
- Assisted manager with new hire processing and existing training programs.
- Initiated timely responses to emails, voicemails, and written correspondence.

# **Technical Support Associate**

IBM, Bangalore

December, 2015 - June, 2017

- Record and classify received Incidents and undertake an immediate effort in order to restore a
  failed IT Service as quickly as possible Assign unresolved Incidents to appropriate Tier 2 Support
  Group Log all Incident/Service Request details, allocating categorization and prioritization codes
  Keep users informed about their Incidents' status at agreed intervals Associate Incidents with other
  records (i.e.
- Incidents, Changes, Problems, Knowledge Articles, Known Errors, etc.) Provide first-line investigation
  and diagnosis of all Incidents and Service Requests Verify resolution with users and resolve
  Incidents in the ITSM tool.
- Escalate Major Incidents to the Incident and/or Problem Manager Escalate Incidents at risk of breaching Service Level Agreement/Operational Level Agreement to the Incident Process.
- Performed quality assurance and quality control assessments of support ticket fulfillment.
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.
- Configured hardware, devices, and software to set up workstations for employees.
- Communicated technical findings via lay terminology to keep interdepartmental teams informed on vital developments.
- Offered remote support for cloud-based and web-based clients via phone, email, and chat.
- Helped streamline repair processes and update procedures for support action consistency.
- Collaborated with vendors to locate replacement components and resolve advanced problems.

# ACHIEVEMENTS

- · Successfully published newsletters for the team.
- Hall of Fame member.
- · Achiever's club member.
- Won the Manager's Choice award multiple times during my tenure